Inventory of the Benjamin A. Rogge papers, 1945-2005
Hoover Institution Archives
Benjamin A. Rogge papers
1945-2005
82054
Hoover Institution Archives
81 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize box (33.5 linear feet)
The collection contains speeches and writings, correspondence, memoranda, reports, and printed matter related to laissez-faire economics and to economic conditions and higher education in the United States.
Rogge, Benjamin A.
Access
Collection is stored off site; a minimum of two days notice is required for use. Boxes may be requested through Stanford's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To view films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1982.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Related Materials
Milton Friedman papers, Hoover Institution Archives
Pierre F. Goodrich papers, Hoover Institution Archives
Mont Pèlerin Society records, Hoover Institution Archives
Foundation for Economic Education miscellaneous correspondence, Hoover Institution Archives
Friedrich A. von Hayek papers, Hoover Institution Archives
F. A. Harper papers, Hoover Institution Archives
Biographical Note
1920 June 18 Born, Hastings, Nebraska
1940 A.B., Mathematics and Economics, Hastings College
1940-1941 Graduate Assistant, Economics, University of
1941-1946 Navigator and Captain, Air Transport Command, U.S.
1942 Married Alice Mabel Landis
1946 M.A., University of Nebraska at Lincoln
1946-1947 Instructor of Economics, University of Minnesota
1947-1949 Instructor of Economics, Northwestern University
1949 Co-author with Herbert Gerhard Heneman, Jobs for All: A Primer of Theory
1949-1953 Assistant Professor of Economics, Wabash College in Crawfordsville, Indiana
1953 Ph.D., Northwestern University
1953-1961, circa Associate Professor of Economics, Wabash College
1954 Co-author with John V. Van Sickle, Introduction to Economics
1955 Visiting professor at the University of Sao Paulo, Brazil, as part of an exchange program under the Smith-Mundt Act
1956 At the invitation of Rogge and John V. Van Sickle, Milton Friedman lectured at Wabash College
1956-1974, circa Lectured during summer session at the University of Michigan for the Public Utility Executive Program
1956-1964 Dean, Wabash College
1959 Author, A Tese de Prebisch
1961-1980, circa Lectured at the Graduate School of Banking at University of Wisconsin-Madison
1964-1980 Distinguished Professor of Political Economy, Wabash College
1966-1980 Director, Wabash Institute for Personal Development
1973 Co-author with Pierre Goodrich, position paper titled Education in a Free Society
1976 Co-editor John Haggarty, The Wisdom of Adam Smith
1978 Honored as Wabash Man of the Year
1978 Received honorary degree from the University of Francisco Marroquin, Guatemala, and from Denison University
1979 Received Outstanding Alumni Award from Hastings College
1979 Author, Can Capitalism Survive?
1980 November Died
Scope and Content of Collection
The papers document the career of Benjamin A. Rogge, an American economist who was a professor and dean of Wabash College. Rogge was a board member of the Liberty Fund, where he worked closely with Pierre Goodrich. He also served on the board of trustees for the Foundation for Economic Education and was a member of the Mont Pèlerin Society. Rogge worked with Milton Friedman on Friedman's TV series Free to Choose and invited Friedman to lecture at Wabash College in 1956. The collection contains speeches and writings, correspondence, memoranda, reports, and printed matter related to laissez-faire economics and to economic conditions and higher education in the United States.
In addition to lecturing at Wabash College, Rogge spoke at a variety of conferences, often to groups of non-economists. Rogge was known for his sense of humor, which he demonstrated in his numerous speeches, many of which covered topics such as the free enterprise system and laissez-faire economics. The speaking engagements, conferences, and meetings file documents conferences, seminars, and board meetings that Rogge spoke at, organized, attended, or considered attending. Materials include correspondence, speeches, and conference materials. For a large part of his career, Rogge lectured at the Public Utility Executive Program at the University of Michigan and at the Graduate School of Banking at the University of Wisconsin-Madison. Materials from these lectures can be found in this file, as well as documents of groups that Rogge was a member of, including the Mont Pèlerin Society, the Liberty Fund, the Foundation for Economic Education, and the Philadelphia Society.
In addition to speeches found in the speaking engagements file, Rogge's speeches and writings can be found throughout the collection where noted, including in boxes 4, 6, 15-18, 30-36, 45, 67, and 79-81. For a bibliography of Rogge's works and description of his speaking engagements, see box 55.
Rogge was concerned about the ability of capitalism to continue as an economic system, an interest which was influenced by the insights of Joseph Schumpeter (Lee). In 1979, the Liberty Fund published Can Capitalism Survive?, a collection of Rogge's speeches examining economic and individual freedom. For materials concerning this work, see boxes 6, 32, 35, and 81.
In the late 1960s, Rogge gave a talk at Cornell entitled "The Welfare State Against the Negro," which he composed from chapters of a book he was writing about economics and race. Thomas Sowell, a professor at Cornell at the time, was not on campus for Rogge's talk, but he wrote to Rogge asking for a copy of the speech, which prompted discussion about Rogge's work (box 6, folder 17). When Rogge realized he was not going to finish writing the book, he gave the manuscript to Sowell, who credits Rogge with the inspiration for applying economic concepts to racial issues (Riley). Rogge's book chapters concerning economics and race can be found in boxes 35, 67, 72, and 81.
Rogge worked on several films and the TV series Free to Choose (box 5). Boxes 6, 11, 34, 35 and 43 have material on the film series Industrial Revolution, which was sponsored by the Liberty Fund and narrated by Rogge. Material on another film narrated by Rogge, Adam Smith and the Wealth of Nations, can be found in boxes 52 and 53.
Rogge filed much of his correspondence in his alphabetical files. For this correspondence, see the single letter files in the alphabetical file found in boxes 1 through 4 and boxes 44 through 47. The subject files in boxes 25 through 31, which are interspersed with Rogge's writings, were most likely used as research for his speeches and articles. The majority of the alphabetical files and subject files retain their original folder titles.
Sources:
Feulner, Edwin J. Foreword. "The Case for Economic Freedom." By Benjamin A. Rogge. The Heritage Foundation, 2008.
Lee, Dwight R. Introduction. A Maverick's Defense of Freedom. By Benjamin A. Rogge. Indianapolis: Liberty Fund, 2010.
Riley, Jason L. "Classy Economist: The Weekend Interview with Thomas Sowell." Wall Street Journal. 25 March 2006.
Economists.; Education--United States.; Free enterprise.; United States--Economic conditions--1945-; Universities and colleges--United States.
- Alphabetical file (Folder 1-5)
  Scope and Contents note
  Includes correspondence, clippings, and printed matter. Single letter folders contain correspondence grouped by name. Includes files related to speeches and writings. See also boxes 44 through 47.
  - A, 1976-1980 (Folder 1: 1)
  - Reservations for the use of the Adam Smith film, 1976 (Folder 1: 2)
  - B, 1973-1980 (Folder 1: 3)
  - Books loaned from Rogge's office, 1976 (Folder 1: 4)
  - Brazil - letters, business arrangements, etc., 1955 (Folder 1: 5)
  - C, 1966-1980 (Folder 1: 6)
  - Campus and civil disorders, 1969, undated (Folder 1: 7)
  - Citizens Cabinet Project, 1977 (Folder 1: 8)
  - Colgate, 1961-1962 (Folder 1: 9)
  - Cornell Alumni Committee, 1961-1971 (Folder 1: 10)
  - D, 1970-1980 (Folder 1: 11)
  - Synopsis of Dissent (student, black panther, etc.), undated (Folder 1: 12)
  - Crawfordsville Electric Light and Power Valuation Report by Lyle E. Fogel and Benjamin A. Rogge, 1977 (Folder 1: 13)
  - Diamond, Art, 1977-1980 (Folder 2: 1)
  - Donnelley Seminar Series, 1969 (Folder 2: 2)
  - Dryden Press review of study guide to Dolan, Basic Economics, 1978-1979 (Folder 2: 3)
  - E, 1965-1980 (Folder 2: 4)
  - Economics, graduate study in England, 1969 (Folder 2: 5)
  - Eisenhower National Graduate Scholarship, 1978 (Folder 2: 6)
  - F, 1965-1980 (Folder 2: 7)
  - Financing higher education, 1965-1970, undated (Folder 2: 8)
    Includes writings by Rogge
  - Foreign study, 1970-1972 (Folder 2: 9)
  - Graduate school correspondence, 1978 (Folder 2: 10)
  - G, 1966-1980 (Folder 3: 1)
  - H, 1967-1980 (Folder 3: 2)
  - High school economics textbook, 1962 (Folder 3: 3)
  - Hillsdale College, Michigan, 1972-1979 (Folder 3: 4)
  - Hoover Institution, 1974-1976 (Folder 3: 5)
  - I, 1965-1980 (Folder 3: 6)
  - Industrial relations, 1970-1971 (Folder 3: 7)
  - J, 1966-1980 (Folder 3: 8)
  - K, 1966-1980 (Folder 4: 1)
  - Kansas-Nebraska Natural Gas Company, annual report, 1975 (Folder 4: 2)
  - Kemper, John, 1970-1974 (Folder 4: 3)
  - Kendall's college, 1967-1969 (Folder 4: 4)
  - Kristol, Irving lecture on Wabash campus (April 1977), 1977-1978 (Folder 4: 5)
  - L, 1964-1980 (Folder 4: 6)
  - Liberty Fund, 1973-1980 (Folder 4: 7)
  - Mc, 1966-1980 (Folder 4: 8)
- Speaking engagements, conferences, and meetings file (Folder 4)
  - Appalachian Hardwood Manufacturers, Inc., Atlanta, Georgia, 1981 (Folder 4: 9)
  - Centenary College of Louisiana and Frost Foundation, Free Enterprise and its Future, 1976-1977 (Folder 4: 10)
  - Interstate Power Company witness, 1980 (Folder 4: 11)
- Speeches and writings (Folder 4-5)
  - General, 1964-1976, undated (Folder 4: 12)
  - Friedman film, Free to Choose, 1975-1979 (Folder 5: 1)
  - Indianapolis Star column, 1980 (Folder 5: 2)
- Speaking engagements, conferences, and meetings file (Folder 5-6)
  - Australian lecture tour, 1976-1977 (Folder 5: 3)
    Includes correspondence with Duncan Yuille
  - Athens University, 1974 (Folder 5: 4)
  - South Dakota Bankers Association, Economic Seminar for Young Adults, Mitchell, South Dakota, 1979-1980 (Folder 5: 5)
  - Campus Ministry Workshop, New Harmony, Indiana, 1967, 1980 (Folder 5: 6)
  - Acapulco, Mexico, 1980 (Folder 5: 7)
  - Board meetings (Folder 5)
    - Kansas-Nebraska Natural Gas Company, 1979-1980 (Folder 5: 8)
    - Earhart Foundation, 1980 (Folder 5: 9)
    - "The Economic Outlook,", 1979-1980 (Folder 5: 10)
    - Foundation for Economic Education, New York, 1980 (Folder 5: 11)
  - Liberty Fund symposiums, 1980 (Folder 5: 12)
  - Liberty Fund and Center for Libertarian Studies colloquium, Role of Efficiency in a Free Society, New York City, 1980 (Folder 5: 13)
  - Elgin Community College, Elgin, Illinois, 1980 (Folder 5: 14)
  - Traverse City State Bank, Michigan, 1980 (Folder 5: 15)
  - First National Bank of Ogden, Champaign, Illinois, 1980 (Folder 5: 16)
  - Economic forecast luncheon, First National Bank of Lansing, Illinois, 1979-1980 (Folder 5: 17-18)
  - Economic forecast luncheon, First National Bank of Lansing, Illinois, 1979-1980 (Folder 5: 19)
  - Association for Modern Banking in Illinois Consumer Credit conference, 1980 (Folder 5: 20)
  - Kennametal, Inc., 1980 (Folder 5: 21)
  - Agricultural Clinic luncheon, Indiana Bankers Association, Purdue University, 1980 (Folder 5: 22)
  - National Asphalt Association, New Orleans, Louisiana, 1980 (Folder 6: 1)
  - Binding Industries of America, 1980 (Folder 6: 2)
  - Convention, 1980 (Folder 6: 3)
  - Edison Electric Institute, Hershey, Pennsylvania, 1980 (Folder 6: 4)
  - Hastings College commencement, 1979-1980 (Folder 6: 5)
  - Liberty Fund Socratic seminar on self and self-interest, 1980 (Folder 6: 6)
  - Financial Executives Institute, Fort Wayne, Indiana, 1980 (Folder 6: 7)
  - Houston, Texas (June 9-11, 1980), undated (Folder 6: 8)
  - Rollins College, Winter Park, Florida, 1978-1980 (Folder 6: 9)
  - College/University Corporation, 1979 (Folder 6: 10)
  - New York City, 1976 (Folder 6: 11)
  - Tom Quirk, Fort Wayne National Bank, 1978 (Folder 6: 12)
  - Harding College, 1978-1980 (Folder 6: 13)
    Includes "Economic Outlook" and "Economics of President Carter After One Year"
  - Clinch Valley College, Wise, Virginia, 1980 (Folder 6: 14)
  - Nassau Club, Princeton, New Jersey, 1980 (Folder 6: 15)
  - Sandusky, Ohio, 1980 (Folder 6: 16)
  - General, 1967-1976 (Folder 6: 17)
    Includes correspondence with Thomas Sowell
- Speeches and writings (Folder 6)
  - Inc. article, 1980 (Folder 6: 18)
  - Can Capitalism Survive?, 1978-1980 (Folder 6: 19)
  - Industrial Revolution film, Liberty Fund, undated (Folder 6: 20)
  - Ira G. Corn, Jr., 1978-1979 (Folder 6: 21)
  - Hong Kong film, Liberty Fund, 1979-1980 (Folder 6: 22)
- Subject file (Folder 6)
  - Vacation, 1978-1979 (Folder 6: 23)
  - Futures Group, 1980, undated (Folder 6: 24-25)
- Speaking engagements, conferences, and meetings file (Folder 7-10)
  - Northern Natural Gas Company, Omaha, Nebraska, 1979-1980 (Folder 7: 1)
  - Zimmer, USA Management Dinner, 1980 (Folder 7: 2)
  - IBM, 1963, 1980 (Folder 7: 3)
  - Graduate School of Banking, University of Wisconsin-Madison, 1979-1980 (Folder 7: 4)
  - Kentucky Bankers Association, Louisville, 1980 (Folder 7: 5)
  - National Asphalt Pavement Association (NAPA) Futures Program, Washington, D.C., 1980 (Folder 7: 6)
  - Kansas Livestock Association Cattle Feeders conference, Great Bend, Kansas, 1980 (Folder 7: 7)
  - Pulliam Fellows, Columbia Club, Indianapolis, 1980 (Folder 7: 8)
  - Foundation for Economic Education, 1980 (Folder 7: 9)
  - IBM, 1980 (Folder 7: 10)
  - Southeastern Lumber Manufacturers Association, New Orleans, Louisiana, 1979-1980 (Folder 7: 11)
  - Peoples Natural Gas, Lake of the Ozarks, Missouri, 1980 (Folder 7: 12)
  - Texas Apartment Association, 1979-1980 (Folder 7: 13)
  - Independent Community Banks of Illinois, 1979-1980 (Folder 7: 14)
  - Trust Divisions of Missouri and Kansas Bankers Associations, 1979-1980 (Folder 7: 15)
  - Edison Electric Institute, Hershey, Pennsylvania, 1979 (Folder 7: 16)
  - Indiana Personnel Association, Indianapolis, 1980 (Folder 7: 17)
  - Liberty Fund seminar on Max Weber, Chicago, Illinois, 1979-1980 (Folder 7: 18)
  - Illinois Bankers Association, Champaign, Illinois, 1979-1980 (Folder 7: 19)
  - Town and Gown Club, Lafayette, Indiana, 1979-1980 (Folder 7: 20)
  - Economic forum, Purdue National Bank, Lafayette, Indiana, 1980 (Folder 7: 21)
  - Old Jail Museum, Great Escapes of the 80s, Strand Theater, Crawfordsville, Indiana, 1979-1980 (Folder 7: 22)
  - Indiana Youth Leadership Seminar, Indianapolis, 1979 (Folder 7: 23)
  - Note on meeting with Dr. Mastin, 1980 (Folder 7: 24)
  - Columbus Area Chamber of Commerce, Columbus, Indiana, 1980 (Folder 7: 25)
  - Kiwanis Club of Indianapolis, 1979 (Folder 7: 26)
  - People's Bank & Trust Company, Bay City, Michigan, 1979-1980 (Folder 7: 27)
  - Indiana Mineral Aggregates Association, Owensboro, Kentucky, 1979-1980 (Folder 7: 28)
  - Public policy seminar on inflation, Crawfordsville, Indiana, 1980 (Folder 7: 29)
  - Foundation for Economic Education, Hudson, New York, 1980 (Folder 7: 30)
  - Paper Converters Association, Tarpon Strings, Florida, 1980 (Folder 7: 31)
  - Indianapolis Chamber of Commerce, 1980 (Folder 7: 32)
  - Home State Bank of Crystal Lake, Business & Professional Leaders, Crystal Lake, Illinois, 1979-1980 (Folder 7: 33)
  - Central Indiana Bankers Installment Credit Association, 1980 (Folder 7: 34)
  - Management and economics seminar, Harding University, Searcy, Arkansas, 1979-1980 (Folder 7: 35)
  - Mont Pèlerin Society general meeting, Hoover Institution, Stanford University, 1980 (Folder 7: 36)
  - Iowa Public Service company management seminar, Steamboat Spring, Colorado, 1978-1980 (Folder 7: 37)
  - National Asphalt Pavement Association 25th Anniversary Convention, Los Angeles, California, 1979-1980 (Folder 7: 38)
  - Indiana Bell, 1980 (Folder 8: 1)
  - Financial Forum Program, Owosso, Michigan, 1979-1980 (Folder 8: 2)
  - Insurance agents meeting, Wabash College, 1979-1980 (Folder 8: 3)
  - Clinton County Purdue AG Club, Frankfort, Indiana, 1979 (Folder 8: 4)
  - Earhart Foundation, 1979-1980 (Folder 8: 5)
  - Central Illinois management conference, Peoria, Illinois, 1978-1980 (Folder 8: 6)
  - College Life Insurance Company of America, 1976-1977 (Folder 8: 7)
  - Institute for Humane Studies Night, 1979 (Folder 8: 8)
  - Foundation for Economic Education seminar, North Andover, Massachusetts, 1979 (Folder 8: 9)
  - Annual economic forecast luncheon, Highland, Indiana, 1978-1979 (Folder 8: 10)
  - IBM executive development conference, New York, 1979 (Folder 8: 11)
  - Foundation for Economic Education, New York, 1979 (Folder 8: 12)
  - Kansas-Nebraska Natural Gas Company board meeting, 1978-1979 (Folder 8: 13)
  - Electric League of Indiana, Indianapolis, 1978-1979 (Folder 8: 14)
  - Great Lakes Caterpillar Dealer Association, San Juan, Puerto Rico, 1979 (Folder 8: 15)
  - Bill Dickneider appointment, 1979 (Folder 8: 16)
  - Northwest Foundation for Economic Education seminar, Olympia, Washington, 1979 (Folder 8: 17)
  - American National Bank in Kalamazoo, 1979 (Folder 8: 18)
    Includes one compact sound cassette
  - Sixth District Federal Home Loan Bank, annual stock holders' meeting, Fort Wayne, Indiana, 1977-1979 (Folder 8: 19)
  - Philadelphia Society national meeting, Chicago, Illinois, 1978 (Folder 8: 20)
  - Foundation for Economic Education seminars, 1976-1978 (Folder 8: 21)
  - College/University Corporation economic seminar, 1978 (Folder 8: 22)
  - Unit Committee of Division of Church and Society of National Council of Churches, Indiana, 1978 (Folder 8: 23)
  - Mississippi Young Bankers Study conference, Hattiesburg, Mississippi, 1977-1978 (Folder 8: 24)
  - Ethel G. Swanback Education Fund, Chamber of Commerce luncheon forum, Sandusky, Ohio, 1977-1978 (Folder 8: 25)
  - Universidad Francisco Marroquin, Guatemala, 1978 (Folder 8: 26)
  - Southeastern Caterpillar Dealers' Association, Boca Raton, Florida, 1977-1978 (Folder 8: 27)
  - National Symposium on Occupational Noise Litigation, Denver, Colorado, 1978 (Folder 8: 28)
  - 25th Annual California Cattle Feeders Association Convention, Palo Alto, California, 1978 (Folder 8: 29)
  - Bell Management Club luncheon, 1977-1978 (Folder 8: 30)
  - Detroit Edison Company Senior Management Committee on Strategic Planning, Troy, Michigan, 1977-1978 (Folder 8: 31)
  - Western Materials' annual meeting, 1978 (Folder 8: 32)
  - Business & Professional Leaders, Home State Bank of Crystal Lake economic seminar, 1977-1978 (Folder 8: 33)
  - National Asphalt Pavement Association, Atlanta, Georgia, 1977-1978 (Folder 8: 34)
  - Indianapolis Downtown Kiwanis Club, 1977-1978 (Folder 8: 35)
  - Miles' Consumer Products Division Sales meeting, Tampa, Florida, 1977-1978 (Folder 8: 36)
  - Indiana Constructors, Inc., Orlando, Florida, 1977-1978 (Folder 8: 37)
  - Service Club of Indianapolis, 1977 (Folder 8: 38)
  - Traverse City State Bank's Fifth Annual Economic Seminar, 1977 (Folder 8: 39)
  - Texas Utilities Management Corp, Texoma, Texas, 1977-1978 (Folder 8: 40)
  - Eastern Indiana Economics Club, Muncie, Indiana, 1977 (Folder 9: 1)
  - Economic outlook luncheon, University of Notre Dame, 1977 (Folder 9: 2)
  - National Wholesale Druggist's Association annual meeting, Florida, 1977-1978 (Folder 9: 3)
  - Group XXIII "Between Sessions" Reunion, Indianapolis, Indiana, 1977 (Folder 9: 4)
  - Institute for Humane Studies symposium on politicization of society, 1977 (Folder 9: 5)
  - Earhart Foundation luncheon, 1977 (Folder 9: 6)
  - Potomac Electric Power Company fall management conference, Washington, D. C., 1977 (Folder 9: 7)
  - First Michigan Bank & Trust Company executive seminar, 1977-1978 (Folder 9: 8)
  - Delaware Power and Light, Baltimore, Maryland, 1977 (Folder 9: 9)
  - American Metal Stamping Association annual meeting, Hilton Head Island, South Carolina, 1977 (Folder 9: 10)
  - Great Lakes Caterpillar Dealer meeting, 1977 (Folder 9: 11)
  - Liberty Fund Socratic seminars, 1977 (Folder 9: 12)
  - Eli Lilly & Company, Phoenix, Arizona, 1977 (Folder 9: 13)
  - Rock-Tenn Company general meeting, Vero Beach, Florida, 1977 (Folder 9: 14)
  - Mud Hollow homecoming weekend, 1977 (Folder 9: 15)
  - Minnesota Bankers Association luncheon, 1977 (Folder 9: 16)
  - South Dakota Bankers Association, 1977 (Folder 9: 17)
  - Kansas Association of Realtors, Topeka, Kansas, 1977 (Folder 9: 18)
  - College/University Corporation Management Group, Indianapolis, Indiana, 1977 (Folder 9: 19)
  - Lubrizol Corporation Board of Directors meeting, Cleveland, Ohio, 1977 (Folder 9: 20)
  - Mach I President's Banquet, Highland, Indiana, 1977 (Folder 9: 21)
  - Chamber of Commerce Industry Appreciation Night, Shelbyville, Indiana, 1977 (Folder 9: 22)
  - Southern Company 12th biennial conference, Georgia, 1977 (Folder 9: 23)
  - Region I Indiana Bankers Association, Fort Wayne, Indiana, 1977 (Folder 9: 24)
  - Executive Development Program, University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, 1978 (Folder 9: 25)
  - Drug Trading Company LTD, Toronto, Ontario, Canada, 1978 (Folder 9: 26)
  - Cleveland alum meeting, 1978 (Folder 9: 27)
  - Central Indiana Bankers Installment Credit Association May meeting, 1978 (Folder 9: 28)
  - Executive Development Program, University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, 1966, 1974-1977 (Folder 9: 29)
  - Liberty Fund Socratic seminars, 1978 (Folder 9: 30)
  - Indiana Savings & Loan Controllers, undated (Folder 9: 31)
  - Southeastern Electric Exchange, annual conference on the engineering and operation division, Washington, D. C., 1978 (Folder 9: 32)
  - Commercial National Bank of Peoria Correspondent Bank Clinic, 1978 (Folder 9: 33)
  - Southern Wholesale Hardware Association Convention, Dallas, Texas, 1978 (Folder 9: 34)
  - Eisenhower Memorial Scholarship Foundation Summer Seminar and Fellowship Weekend, Bloomington, Indiana, 1978 (Folder 10: 1)
  - Foundation for Economic Education seminar, 1978 (Folder 10: 2)
  - Wood Molding & Mill Work Producers, Reno, Nevada, 1978 (Folder 10: 3)
  - Kiwanis Club of Indianapolis, 1978 (Folder 10: 4)
  - Pulliam Fellows, Indianapolis, Indiana, 1978 (Folder 10: 5)
  - Liberty Fund film, 1978 (Folder 10: 6)
  - Foundation for Economic Education, 1978 (Folder 10: 7)
  - Rockford Area Chamber of Commerce annual meeting, Rockford, Illinois, 1978 (Folder 10: 8)
  - Indianapolis Rotary Club, 1978 (Folder 10: 9)
  - Midwest College Placement Association Spring Workshop, Indianapolis, 1978 (Folder 10: 10)
  - South Dakota Bankers Economic seminar for young adults, Mitchell, 1977-1978 (Folder 10: 11)
  - Missouri Chamber of Commerce, 1978 (Folder 10: 12)
  - First Midland Bank & Trust Company executive seminar Day, Midland, Michigan, 1977-1979 (Folder 10: 13)
  - Chicago meeting, 1978 (Folder 10: 14)
  - Edison Electric Institute round table conference, Drake Hotel, Chicago, 1978 (Folder 10: 15)
  - Lafayette Life Insurance Company, Hawaii, 1978 (Folder 10: 16)